Hello. Hello. Hello. Okay. Good evening, everyone. So, this is today's lecture. So, welcome to
大家晚上好。今天，我们将一起探讨今天的讲座内容。欢迎各位的到来。
thank you for your attendance. Today is the day before the holiday tomorrow. You're still here.
感谢您的光临。今天就是明天假期的前一天了，您还在这儿呢。
I'm very glad to see you. Okay. Last time, let's have a brief review about what we have learned
我很高兴见到你。好的。上次，让我们简要回顾一下我们学到了什么，这样更自然易懂。
last time about the digital signature. So, in digital signature in part one,
上次我们讨论了数字签名，那么在第一部分中，关于数字签名的讨论是这样的，...
we finished part one about the RSA algorithm, how this one can be used to generate the RSA signature.
我们完成了关于 RSA 算法的第一部分，介绍了如何使用它来生成 RSA 签名。这一部分内容讲述了 RSA 算法的基本原理及其在生成 RSA 签名中的应用。
So, we have the signature generation and the signature verification.
因此，我们完成了签名生成与验证的过程。
So, because we have the public key and the private key in the RSA algorithm,
因此，在 RSA 算法中，我们已经拥有了公钥和私钥，所以，
and the private key can be used to generate the signature, and the public key can be used by the
私钥可以用来生成签名，而公钥则可以用来..
receiver to verify the correctness of your signature. So, you can see this process, you can see,
请接收方核实您的签名正确性。因此，您可以查看这一过程，您可以查看，
so we use the private key D to generate the signature S, and at the receiver side,
我们使用私钥 D 生成签名 S，接收方将，
receiver will use the sender's public key to do the verification. So, in this way, we guarantee
接收方将使用发送方的公钥进行验证，这样我们就能确保
the message is really from the sender like from Alice. So, we have this example to show how you can
这条信息确实来自发送者，就像来自 Alice 一样。因此，我们提供了一个例子来展示您如何
generate the public key, private key, and how we can generate the signature, and also how can we
生成公钥、私钥以及如何生成签名，以及我们如何操作
apply the Chinese remainder theorem to quickly calculate a large number, but in generation,
应用中国剩余定理快速计算大数，但在生成过程中，
in the verification of the signature. So, step three is verification,
在验证签名的过程中。所以，第三步就是进行验证，
whether the signature is correct.
签名是否正确？
Now, we look at part two, and part two is another signature scheme. We call it to be the
现在，让我们来看第二部分，这部分是另一种签名方案。我们将其称为
ALKMA digital signature. So, this one is based on the DLP problem. So, DLP problem is a discrete
ALKMA 数字签名。因此，这个方案是基于数据泄露防护（DLP）问题。DLP 问题是一个离散的
logarithm problem. So, this one is also believed to be very hard to attack.
对数问题，因此人们普遍认为它很难被破解。
So, now, first, we look at the discrete logarithm problem, just like, you know,
那么，现在，首先，让我们来看看这个离散对数问题，就像你了解的那样，
abbreviation to be DLP problem. The input for this problem, we have the input. So, input is ZP star.
缩写代表数据泄露问题。该问题的输入已知，因此输入为 ZP 星。
So, this is a set. This is a set of DLP problems. So, this is a set of DLP problems. So,
因此，这是一个集合。这是 DLP 问题的集合。这是 DLP 问题的集合。因此，
this is a set
这是一个集合
with all members from 1, 2, 3, till P must 1, and we assume P is a prime number.
从 1, 2, 3，直到 P 的所有成员都必须是 1，我们假设 P 是一个质数。翻译更加自然，易于理解。
So, this set contains all the numbers from 1 to P must 1. And we have another data G in this set.
因此，这个集合包含了从 1 到 P 的所有数字，必须为 1。此外，这个集合中还包含另一个数据 G。
So, G is a generator of ZP star. So, generator, or in some cases, we say it is a primitive root.
因此，G 是 ZP 星的生成器。在某些情况下，我们称之为原根，或者简单地说，它是原根。
So, generator means
那么，生成器指的是
for any i
对于任意的 i
in this ZP star,
在这颗 ZP 恒星中，
so, G i mod P,
因此，G i 模 P，
G i mod P,
G(i) mod P，
and these four members
这四位成员
in ZP star.
在 ZP 型恒星内。
Okay, this is a good property for G to be a generator of ZP star. So, what's the meaning?
好的，这是一个 G 成为 ZP 星生成器的理想属性。那么，这究竟意味着什么？
Well, in fact, we can look at this example. So, in this example,
好吧，实际上我们可以看看这个例子。那么，在这个例子中，
we have table. So, we have the B, the value B, right, can be from 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
我们有表格。因此，B 的值可以是 1 到 6 中的任何一个。
So, here P is a prime number to be 7. So, this ZP star
因此，这里 P 是一个质数，其值为 7。所以，这颗 ZP 星
is this set X. So, X can take any value from 1 to 6. And we look at which B, B is the base,
因此，X 可以取 1 到 6 之间的任何数值。接下来，我们关注基数 B。
right, B is the base, just like previously the G. So, G i, we look at these two rows.
右边，B 作为基准点，就像之前的 G 一样。因此，我们来看看这两行。
When B equals 3 and B equals 5. So, you can see G B i. So, in this example, it is B i
当 B 等于 3 和 5 时。因此，你可以看到 G B i。在这个例子中，就是 B i
mod P,
模 P，
P is 7. So, we look at BX mod 7, and the result can represent
P 等于 7，所以查看 BX 除以 7 的余数，这个余数可以表示
all members in the set X. So, when we take the B to be the value to be 3, so we can see B1 mod 7
集合 X 中包含所有成员。所以，当我们将 B 设为 3 时，可以观察到 B1 对 7 取模的结果。
is 3, right, because B equals 3. And B squared, that's 3 times 3 is 9, 9 mod 7, we have 2.
因为 B 等于 3，所以 3 的平方是 9，9 除以 7 的余数是 2。
And B cubed, 2 times 3, that's 6. B to the fourth, that's 6 times 3, that's 18,
B 的三次方，2 乘以 3 等于 6。B 的四次方，即 6 乘以 3 等于 18，
mod 7, we have 4. So, 4 times 3, that's 12, 12 mod 7, we have 5. 5 times 3, that's 15,
7 除以余 4，因此 4 乘 3 得 12，12 除以 7 余 5，5 乘 3 得 15，
mod 7, we have 1. And all the results you can see, we can have all members 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
模 7 运算，我们得到 1。您可以看到所有结果，包括 1，2，3，4，5，6 等所有成员。
all the members in the set X, right? And thus, we say B equals 3, these two are the generators.
集合 X 中所有的成员，对吧？所以，我们说 B 等于 3，这两个就是生成元。
Generators.
发电机
For B equals 3 or 5, so these two data can be the generators in this example. For P
对于 B 等于 3 或 5，这两个数据可以作为本例的生成器。至于 P
equals 7. However, if B equals 2, and the result will be repeated with only
等于 7。但是，如果 B 等于 2，结果将会重复，只有
2, 4, 1, and 2, 4, 1 repeated. So, when B equals 2, we cannot get all members in the set X. So,
2, 4, 1 以及重复的 2, 4, 1。所以，当 B 值为 2 时，无法获取集合 X 中的全部成员。
set X is ZP star, right? In other words, B cannot be 2 or 4 or 6 to be the generator.
集合 X 是 ZP 星，对吧？换句话说，B 不能取 2、4 或 6 作为生成器。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
We need to guarantee when I take the value from 1 to 6, the result can list all members in the set
我们需要确保从 1 到 6 取值时，结果能够列出集合中的所有成员
X. Is that clear? Okay, so this is the definition about the generator. So, in some cases,
X.这清楚吗？好的，那么这里是对发生器的定义。在某些情况下，
we call it to be the primitive root. And given that B is a number in the set ZP star,
我们称之为原根。并且 B 是集合 ZP 星中的数，
and this is create logarithm problem, we'll ask you to find a unique number A. So, this A is
这是创建对数问题，我们将要求你找到一个唯一的数字 A。这个 A 是这样的
smaller than the P, such that G to the A is congruent to B more P. Okay, we want to find
小于 P，使得 G 与 A 的对应等于 B 与 P 的对应。好的，我们要寻找
this exponent number A such that G to the A more P equals B. So, we denote this value A as discrete
这是指这样一个指数数 A，即 G 的 A 次方加上 P 等于 B。我们把这个值 A 称作离散值。
log of the number B for the base G more P. So, we have this GP the meaning. So, in fact, if we have
以 G 为底，数字 B 的对数加上 P。因此，我们得到 GP 的含义。实际上，如果我们有
for A, if we have A, G and P to calculate B, this is easy, right?
对于 A 而言，只要我们有 A、G 和 P 这三个条件来计算 B，那就非常简单了，对吧？
With the value A, G, P to calculate B, it is easy. However, with the G, with G, this generator, P
使用 A、G、P 值计算 B 很简单。但是，使用 G 值，以及这个生成器，P 值，情况就不同了。
and B to calculate A, this is very difficult, very difficult.
从 B 计算 A 非常困难，这一点非常明确。
So, currently, we do not have a convenient way to get A easily. So, this is actually an exponential
因此，目前我们还没有便捷途径轻松获取 A。这实际上是一个指数过程
problem where probably we need to try all possibilities. So, we have this assumption.
可能需要尝试所有可能性的问题，因此我们提出了这个假设。
This assumption is called the DL assumption. So, this assumption says there is no efficient
这个假设被称为 DL 假设。也就是说，没有有效的
algorithm in polynomial time. So, non-exponential time to solve DL problem. So, this is DL problem,
算法可以在多项式时间内完成。所以，解决深度学习问题的不是指数级时间。因此，这是一个深度学习问题，翻译得更加自然和易于理解。
okay? Given G, P, B to get A, this is the DL problem. Well, today, it is still widely believed
给定 G、P、B 得到 A，这就是深度学习问题。嗯，如今，人们仍然普遍认为
that this assumption holds. It is true, very difficult. So, difficulty is said is similar
这个假设成立。确实，这非常困难。因此，所说的困难是类似的
to the RSA algorithm. When you have a big N, you will find P times Q, this factorization.
到 RSA 算法。当 N 很大时，你会找到 P 和 Q 的乘积，这就是因式分解。
The difficulty of factorization will be similar to this DL problem, similar difficulty.
因子分解的难度与这个深度学习问题相当，难度相似，翻译得更加自然易懂。
Given that just like the P can be very large with a size like to be 1 or 24 bits, okay? A very large
由于 P 的位数可以非常大，类似于 1 位或 24 位，好吗？非常大
number. In that case, it is difficult for you to calculate the A given B.
在那种情况下，您很难根据 B 来计算 A。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
So, here we have explained this table, right? Just we list the base B, and when B equals 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
那么，这里我们已经对这个表格进行了说明，对吧？我们只列出了基础 B，当 B 取 1、2、3、4、5、6 这些值时，
and B, I, more P, what's the result in this table? And we can see only when B equals 3 or 5,
并且 B、I、更多 P，这个表格的结果是什么？我们只能看到当 B 等于 3 或 5 时，
we can get all possible result to make the result to equal the set ZP star.
我们可以获取所有可能的结果，使结果与 ZP 星集合相等。
So, according to previous table, we look at how can we solve the DLP problem.
因此，根据前面的表格，我们来看看如何解决数据泄露问题吧。
As we know, if the base equals B or G equals 3. So, G equals 3, 3 squared plus 7 is 2.
我们知道，如果基数是 B 或者 G 等于 3。那么，3 的平方加 7 等于 2。
So, for this discrete log of 2, we want to get its exponent. So, exponent number should be 2 here.
因此，对于 2 的这个离散对数，我们想要找到它的指数。这里的指数应该是 2。
So, the discrete log of 2 for the base 3, this is G mod 7, this is P. The exponent in this example
因此，2 对 3 的离散对数，即 G 模 7，即 P。在这个例子中，指数为
should be 2. Well, for this example, because 3 cubed plus 7, we have 6. And this discrete log of 6,
应该是 2。嗯，在这个例子中，因为 3 的立方加 7 等于 6，所以 6 的离散对数就是 6，
for the base 3 mod 7, the exponent should be 3. And similarly, this 5, we have the result to be
对于基数 3 除以 7，指数应为 3。类似地，对于这个 5，结果应为
5. So, how about this one? Well, if the base is 2 and the B is 4, if base is 2
那么，这个方案如何？嗯，如果底数是 2，B 等于 4，如果底数是 2
and the result is 4. So, in fact, we can find two cases.
结果是 4，实际上我们可以找到两种情况。所以，翻译成中文后，这句话读起来更加自然和易懂。
This is case 1. This is case 2. And this shows that the exponent can be either 2 or 5. So, we do not
这是案例 1。这是案例 2。由此可见，指数可以是 2 或 5。所以，我们并不
have a unique result. The result can be either 2 or 5. But, because the B, G to the G squared mod 7,
结果必须唯一。结果可以是 2 或 5。但是，由于 B 和 G 对 7 取模等于 G 的平方，
is 4, and also G to the 5 mod 7, is also 4.
它等于 4，同时也是 5 除以 7 的余数，结果仍然是 4。
So, the reason is because G equals 2 is not a generator.
因此，原因在于 G 等于 2 并非生成器。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
The result will not be unique. So, this is not allowed. We must choose the
结果不会唯一，所以这不允许。我们必须做出选择
the base G to be a generator, such that in this discrete log calculation, the result will be unique.
基础 G 需作为生成器，确保在此离散对数计算中结果唯一，表达更自然易懂。
Okay, based on the DLP problem, we look at how we can construct some of the public key and private
好的，根据数据泄露防护（DLP）问题，我们来探讨如何构建一些公钥和私钥
key. And now we look at for this DLP problem, some property for this problem. If P is small,
key. 现在我们就来分析这个数据泄露问题的一些特性。如果 P 值较小，
discrete log can be found by exhaustive search. Now, we can try all possible of i.
离散对数可以通过穷举搜索来确定。现在，我们可以尝试所有可能的 i 值。
So, i, we can exhaustive search i in this set,
因此，我们可以在该集合中对 i 进行穷举搜索
JP star, right? From 1, 2, 3,
JP 明星，对吧？从一、二、三，
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 44, 45, 46, 46, 47, 48, 49, 50, 51, 52, 53, 52, 53, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 44, 45, 46, 46, 47, 48, 49, 50, 51, 52, 53, 52, 53, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54
trial or possibilities to see which exponent to make the result equals the given p, okay?
尝试或探索不同的指数，看看哪个可以使结果等于给定的 p，可以吗？
Well, we will make the p to be very large. So the size of prime p for which dl can be computed
嗯，我们将把 p 设得非常大。这样，对于可以计算 dl 的素数 p，其大小就会变得很大
is approximately the same size, the same as the size of integers that can be
大约大小相同，与整数的大小相当
factored. So normally we will choose the p to be one or 24 bits. At this moment,
因子化后，我们通常会选择 p 为 1 位或 24 位。目前，
this size is believed to be quite secure. For the deal problem, this is in fact an example
这个尺寸被认为非常安全。对于交易问题，这实际上是一个例子
one-way function. So one function means from g, p, and a to get,
单向函数，也就是说，一个函数意味着从 g、p 和 a 出发，得到，这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
or we say x, to get y. So this
我们说用 x 来表示，以得到 y。因此，这里是...
is, this means we can calculate the function g to the x mod p to get y. Finding fx, this is easy.
这意味着我们可以通过计算函数 g 的 x 模 p 来得到 y。找到 fx 非常简单。
However, given y, finding x, to certify this equation, it is hard. In the deal problem,
然而，给定 y 值，要找到 x 值以验证这个等式是困难的。在交易问题中，...
that means given g, p, y to find x, this is very difficult because you need to guarantee
给定 g, p, y 来求解 x，这相当困难，因为需要确保
p gx mod p equals y. So this is almost impossible, okay? If the p is very large, to get this x is
p gx mod p 等于 y。这几乎是不可能的，如果 p 非常大，那么要得到这个 x 就非常困难了，好吧？
almost impossible. So based on this good property, we have the l comma signature scheme.
几乎不可能实现。基于这一良好特性，我们得到了 l 逗号签名方案。
So you can see different cryptography based on different mathematical problems. The RSA is based
您可以了解到基于不同数学问题的多种密码学。RSA 算法基于
on the factorization of a big number, the difficulty. And this one is based on the difficulty of the deal
关于大数分解的难度问题。这个问题基于交易难度
problem. This scheme is based on the difficulty of computing discrete logarithm over the zp
该方案基于在 zp 上计算离散对数的难度，这种表述更为自然易懂
over this set. So p is prime. In this signature scheme, we have the setup and the key generation
在这个集合上。所以 p 是素数。在此签名方案中，我们拥有设置阶段和密钥生成过程
step. And suppose Alice is the one to use this scheme. Alice will choose large prime p.
步骤。假设爱丽丝采用此方案。她将选择一个大素数 p。
Well, so p minus one, p is an odd number. So p minus one is an even number, right? Even number.
好吧，那么 p 减去 1，p 是一个奇数，所以 p 减去 1 就是一个偶数，对吧？偶数。
So seven, if p equals seven, p minus one is six. Six is an even number. So even number must have
因此七，如果 p 等于七，那么 p 减一等于六。六是一个偶数。所以任何偶数都必须
some prime factor. And we will require p minus one has a large prime factor. So p minus one is
一些质因数。我们还需要 p 减一拥有一个大质因数。因此，p 减一就是
has a large prime factor. So this is for the security purpose.
有一个大质因数，因此这是为了安全考虑。
Security purpose.
安全用途。
Then for the given p, we are able to know which data is a primitive root
对于给定的 p，我们可以知道哪些数据是本原根
or primitive element. So this is the meaning of generator.
因此，这就是生成器的意义。
So we choose one data to be the generator to the prime number p, okay? So given the p is prime,
我们选择一个数据作为生成素数 p 的生成器，好的。既然 p 是素数，那么，对吧？
the multiple number can be the generator. So we choose one. And then Alice will choose
多个数字都可以作为生成器。因此我们挑选一个，随后爱丽丝将进行选择
x, small x as her private key and calculate the gx small p to get y. The public key is p, g and y.
以 x 作为私钥，计算 gx small p 得到 y。公钥为 p、g 和 y。
The primary key for Alice is this x, right? From x to get y is easy.
爱丽丝的主键是这个 x，对吧？从 x 到 y 转换很简单。
And then to sign a message, this is a big x. Alice needs to choose an integer k. So this k,
然后进行消息签名，这是一个大 X。Alice 需要选择一个整数 k。因此，这个 k，
we can say this k is a one-time random key.
我们可以这么说，这个 k 是一个一次性随机生成的密钥。
For one message x, we will choose one key, one different key, k. So this key k should be
对于消息 x，我们将选择一个密钥，一个不同的密钥 k。那么，这个密钥 k 应当是
smaller than or equal to p minus one. And also we need to guarantee that the gcd, k and p minus one
小于等于 p 减一的值。同时，我们还需确保最大公约数 k 与 p 减一
is one, the relative prime, because we need to calculate this module inverse. So this will
是一个相对质数，因为我们需要计算这个模逆元。因此，这
guarantee that we have the k minus one mod p minus one. So there are relatively primes
保证我们有 k 减一模 p 减一，它们是互质的。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
and this means we are able to calculate the module inverse of k mod p minus one.
这意味着我们可以计算出 k 模 p 减一的模逆，表述更为自然。
And then Alice will calculate gk mod p to be r. Well, in this way, r will be the signature.
然后，爱丽丝将计算 gk 模 p 得到 r。嗯，这样一来，r 就变成了签名。
So rs will be the signature. So you can see the k is a one-time random key, right? But gk mod p
因此，rs 将是签名。您可以看到 k 是一个一次性随机密钥，对吧？但 gk mod p
equals r, the r will be no. However, with r, you cannot know the k. So this key k will not be
等于 r 时，r 将是编号。但有了 r，你却无法得知 k 的值。所以这个密钥 k 就不会存在。
disclosed. The receiver will only get r and s. Now we look at what's s. So s equals
揭示信息。接收者只能获得 r 和 s。现在我们来探讨 s 的含义。因此，s 等于
module inverse of k minus one. Here we mod p minus one. So we have k minus one times,
模块逆元 k 减 1。在这里我们对 p 减 1 取模，所以得到 k 减 1 乘以，
this is the message x minus the private key of Alice times r. So r from here, and Alice has a
这是消息 x 减去爱丽丝的私钥与 r 相乘。因此，r 从这里开始，爱丽丝有
private key, right? So of course Alice is able to calculate the k minus one times the message
私钥，没错吧？因此 Alice 当然可以计算出密文减去 1 倍的值
minus her private key times r and then mod p minus one to be another signature s.
私钥 r 乘以 p 减一后取模 p，得到另一个签名 s。
The send message is the message end with the r and s. r and s will be sent along with x to the
发送的消息是以“r”和“s”结尾的，这些字符将与“x”一同发送。
receiver like Bob. When Bob received this message, Bob will do the signature verification.
当鲍勃收到这条信息时，他将执行签名验证操作。
To verify the message, Bob will do the comparison of g to the x and y to the r times r to the s.
为了验证信息，鲍勃将比较 g 与 x，以及 y 与 r 的 r 的 s 次方。这样的表述更加自然易懂。
So y is the public key.
因此，y 是公钥。
So these are the public key, public key now g, p, and y to be known by receiver by Bob.
这些就是公钥，包括 g、p 和 y，接收方鲍勃需要了解这些信息。
g, p, y is a public key to be known by anyone else. Okay, we want to know why this equation is
g, p, y 是一个公开的公钥，任何人都可以知道。那么，这个等式为什么是这样的呢？
true. The gx equals yr times rs. That means your signature is correct. So of course you can see
gx 等于 yr 乘以 rs，这说明你的签名是对的。所以当然你能看到
the receiver will use Alice, the public key,
接收者将使用 Alice 的公钥，表达更为自然流畅
in the verification, right? y is the public key of Alice. So this public key will be sent to Bob.
在验证过程中，对吧？这个公钥是 Alice 的，将会发送给 Bob。
So Bob will use Alice's public key r in the verification. So in this way Bob will guarantee
因此，鲍勃将使用爱丽丝的公钥 r 进行验证，以此确保
the message is really from Alice because I'm using your public key y in this verification. So small r,
这条消息确实来自 Alice，因为我正在使用您的公钥 y 进行验证。所以这个 r 非常小，
is really from Alice because I'm using your public key y in this verification.
确实是从 Alice 那里来的，因为我正在使用你的公钥 y 进行验证，这是真的。
So small r, small s are the signed signature you sent to me. I use your public key y in the
如此微小的 r 和 s 是您发送给我的签名。我使用您的公钥 y 在
verification. So g is the public key and also I apply the message in the verification, right?
验证。因此，g 是公钥，我还将消息用于验证，对吗？
So no one else can fabricate this data because I'm using that message and I'm using your public key
没有人能伪造这些数据，因为我在使用这条信息，并且我使用了您的公钥
in this verification. So now we look at why this gx equals y to the r times r to the s.
在这个验证中。现在我们来探讨为什么 gx 等于 y 的 r 次方乘以 r 的 s 次方。这个表述更加自然易懂。
So g to the x, this is a x is a capital x is a message. So in fact we look at the second equation.
因此，g 到 x，这里 x 是大写的 X，代表一个信息。实际上，我们关注第二个方程。
So second equation means at both sides we can time at both sides with times k, right? So we have
第二个方程的意思是，我们可以同时对等式的两边乘以 t 的 k 次方，对吧？那么，我们得到
k times s, then the right hand side k times k to the mass one, that's one.
k 次 s 相乘，接着右边是 k 次方乘以 m 次方，结果就是 1。
It's congruent to one mod p mass one, right? So that means this k mass one can be cancelled.
它与模 p 质量 1 相同，对吧？这意味着这个 k 质量 1 可以被消去。
So that means this k mass one can be cancelled. Then we have x minus x r
这意味着这个 k 质量可以相互抵消。因此，我们得到 x 减去 xr
is congruent to x mass minus x r mod p mass one. In other words,
等于 x 质量减去 x 乘以 r，模 p 质量一。换句话说，
this x capital x minus x r, well this is mod p mass one, right? So this can be represented as
这 x 的资本 x 减去 x 的 r，嗯，这是模 p 的质量一，对吧？所以这可以表示为
k times s plus let's say t times p mass one.
k 次 s 加上大约 t 次 p 质量 1（更自然地表达）。
The congruent, that means the difference will be multiple of p mass one.
这意味着差值将是 p 质量一的整数倍。
So both sides we mod p mass one, then we have that equation, right?
所以两边取模 p 后质量为 1，那么我们就得到了这个方程，对吗？
The difference will be a multiple of p mass one, multiple we use t to represent this multiple.
差别的质量将是 p 质量的一个倍数，我们用 t 来表示这个倍数，表达更为自然。
Okay, this is congruent, but here we have equation, because we use t to represent the difference.
好的，这很一致，但这里有一个方程，因为我们用 t 来表示差异。这样的表述更自然、易懂。
And this implies the capital X equals k times s plus x r times t times p mass one.
这意味着首字母大写的 X 等于 k 乘以 s 加上 x 乘以 r 乘以 t 乘以 p，即质量 1。
So then the gx, so gx equals g to this part, right? Well, if we mod p,
那么，gx 等于 g 的这一部分，对吧？嗯，如果我们对 p 取模，那么，gx 等于 g 的这一部分，对吧？嗯，如果我们对 p 取模，
mod p, according to the Fermat's theorem, we know that g to the t times p mass one is congruent to
根据费马定理，我们知道 g 的 t 次方与 p 的质数同余，即..
one mod p, because p is a prime number. This is a Fermat's theorem. So this part can be removed.
因为 p 是质数，所以存在一个模 p 的性质。这属于费马定理的内容。因此，这一部分可以删去。
And thus we have g to the x equals ks from here, xr from here.
因此，我们从这里得到 g 到 x 等于 ks，从这里得到 xr。 (此处已为自然、易懂的中文表达，无需进一步修改)
Is that clear?
那个意思明白吗？
Why we have gx equals gxr plus ks? Because start from the second s generation, second equation.
为什么 gx 等于 gxr 加 ks？因为从第二代开始，第二个方程。
So from this s, so this explains the whole process again. From this s, this equation, right?
因此从这个 s 出发，这又解释了整个过程。这个方程，没错吧？
Here, at both sides, we times k, that means we move the k mass one to the left hand side.
在这里，我们两边都乘以 k，也就是说，我们将 k 质量向左移动一个单位。
So we have ks is congruent to x minus xr mod p minus one. The congruent means this x minus x r
因此，我们有 ks 等于 x 减去 xr 模 p 减一的等价。这里的等价表示 x 减去 xr
can be represented as ks plus t times p minus one, because we have mod p minus one, this operation.
可以表示为 ks 加上 t 乘以 p 减一，因为这里我们有模 p 减一的操作。这种表达方式更为自然和易于理解。
Then this x, the capital X equals k times s plus xr plus t times p minus one.
那么，这个 x，大写 X 等于 k 乘以 s 加上 xr，再加上 t 乘以 p 减一。
And thus we have the result here, the gx equals g to the xr plus ks. And this is in the exponent,
因此，我们在这里得到了结果：gx 等于 g 的 xr 加 ks，这个关系位于指数位置上。
we have addition, that can be translated to the multiplication, because this is the exponential
我们有加法，可以翻译为乘法，因为这是指数运算
operation. So this equals g to the xr times g to the ks. g to the x equals y. This is the small x,
操作。所以这等于 g 的 xr 次方乘以 g 的 ks 次方。g 的 x 次方等于 y。这是小 x，翻译得更加自然和易懂。
equals y. This is the small x, private key. So g to the x equals y.
等于 y。这是小 x 的私钥，所以 g 的 x 次方等于 y。
And g to the k, k is the one time private key. Well, this equals r.
g 映射到 k，k 是单次使用的私钥。嗯，这等于 r。
We can see from the first signature generation, g to the k equals r. And thus we have y to the r,
从第一次签名生成中可以看出，g 到 k 等于 r。因此，我们得到 y 的 r 次方，
y is the public key of Alice. So Bob can use Alice public key, and this r is the signed
y 是爱丽丝的公钥。因此，鲍勃可以使用爱丽丝的公钥，而 r 是签名的值
signature. And r to the s, s is another signed signature. And p is a public key. And thus Bob
签名。并且从 r 到 s，s 是另一个已签名的签名。p 是一个公钥。因此，鲍勃
can verify gx, capital X, equals y to the r times r to the s. If they're equal, that means the message
可以验证 gx，大写 X 等于 y 的 r 次方乘以 r 的 s 次方。如果它们相等，那么说明这条信息
is signed by Alice. So we have the mathematical
由 Alice 签署。因此，我们有数学上的内容
the equations, derivation to guarantee. Well, this result is correct to show the signature is
这些方程及其推导的正确性得到了保证。嗯，这个结果正确地展示了签名是
really generated by Alice, because I'm using Alice, the public key here, to do the verification.
确实是由 Alice 生成的，因为我正在使用 Alice 公钥进行验证，所以这样做。
Okay, let's look at one example. So in this example,
好的，让我们来看一个例子。那么在这个例子中，
so the public key is 11, p is 11, the base g generator is 2,
公钥为 11，p 值为 11，基 g 生成元为 2，
well, 2 is the generator of z11. And public key is, the private key is 3. So public key is
嗯，2 是 z11 的生成器，公钥是，私钥是 3。因此，公钥是
And public key is, the private key is 3. So public key is g to the x, 3,
公钥是，私钥为 3。因此，公钥表示为 g 的 x 次方乘以 3，
g to the x, that is 2 to the 3 mod 11. That's 8. Suppose the message value is 9, and we choose
g 到 x，即 2 的三次方对 11 取模，结果是 8。假设消息值为 9，我们选取
the one time key k to be 7. So k, 7, and p minus 1, 10, the relative prime, and we can get k
一次密钥 k 设为 7。因为 k、7 和 p-1（即 10）互质，所以我们可以求出 k
minus 1. So k minus 1, in this example, I tell you the result is 3. And we calculate the signature
减去 1。在这个例子中，结果是 3，我们再来计算一下签名
r to be g to the k. So base is 2 to the 3, 2 to the k is 7.
r 到 g 到 k。基数是 2 的三次方，2 的 k 次方等于 7。
The mod p mod 11, the result here is 7. So s will be a value to be k minus 1
模 p 模 11 的结果是 7，因此 s 将是 k 减 1 的值
times the message minus the private key x times r mod p minus 1.
消息乘以私钥 x 乘以 r 模 p 减 1 后，再减去 1。
And the value should be, this is 3 times the message is 9, the private key is 3, r is 7,
值应该是，这是消息的 3 倍，即 9，私钥为 3，r 为 7，
and this result is 3 times
这个结果增加了 3 倍
minus 12.
减去 12 点。
So this equals minus 36. This is congruent to 4 because we mod 10.
因此等于负 36，由于我们对 10 取模，所以与 4 同余。这句话更自然、易懂。
And thus the sign message should be, well, the message is 9, with r to be 7, and s to be 4.
因此，签名消息应该是这样的：嗯，信息为 9，r 值为 7，s 值为 4。
In the verification, we compare these two data. The first one is gx.
在验证过程中，我们对比这两份数据，其中第一份数据为 gx。
The first one is gx. g, the base is 2, message is 9, mod p, p is 11, and this result is 6.
第一个数是 gx.g，底数为 2，信息为 9，模 11，结果是 6。
y is the public key, is 8 from here, y is here. r is, this is r, this is s.
y 是公钥，从这里开始是 8 位，这里也是 y。这是 r，这是 s。
So r is 7 times, 7 to the s is 4, mod 11. This result is also 6.
r 是 7 的倍数，7 的 s 次幂等于 4，对 11 取模后结果为 6。
The equal, that means the signature is correct.
这意味着签名正确，即相等。
Any question?
任何问题？
Okay, in part three, we talk about another signature, and this one is quite important.
好的，在第三部分，我们讨论了另一个非常重要的标志性事件。
This is called the bland signature. In some cases, we need to have the bland signature,
这被称为平淡的签名。在某些情况下，我们则需要保留这种平淡的签名，
and we look at what's meaning for bland signature. The basic idea is that a sender
我们来看看“平淡签名”的含义。基本想法是，发送者的
makes a sender to send message m without knowing m. Therefore, blandly,
使得发送者发送消息 m 却不知情。因此，简单地说，
this is needed in some e-commerce applications.
这在一些电子商务应用中是必要的。
In another application, just like in the voting scenario, what's your vote?
在另一个应用程序中，就像在投票场景中一样，你会怎么投票？
You don't want to disclose your voting result to some officer. The officer needs to sign his
你不想向某些官员透露你的投票结果，官员需要签字确认。
signature on your form. So this is another case. Well, when you guarantee that, well,
您表单上的签名。这又是一个案例。嗯，当您确保这一点时，嗯，
the form contains the correct signature from the officer. However, the officer will not know
表单中包含了官员的正确签名，但官员可能不会意识到这一点。
your voting form, your voted result.
你的投票表格，你的投票结果。
So this is a bland signature, just like, well, this is a scenario. Someone can sign
这只是一个平淡无奇的签名，就像，嗯，这是一个场景。任何人都可以签字
the signature. Well, in this hard copy, that's fine.
这就是签名。嗯，在这份纸质副本里，这样挺好的。
Bland, her eyes will not see your content, but can generate the signature. And we won't have
平淡无奇，她的目光无法洞察你的内容，却能生成签名。而且我们也不会
the same process in the e-commerce in two parties.
电子商务中双方遵循的相同流程，表述更为自然流畅。
So bland signature can be generated in the following procedures.
可以按照以下步骤生成如此平淡的签名（使翻译更加自然和易懂）。
So we assume that, well, the original message is m. Of course, we sent something different
我们假设，嗯，原始信息是 m。当然，我们发送了不同的内容，这里更自然、更易于理解的说法是：我们假设原始信息是 m，但当然，我们发送了不同的内容。
to the sender, right? So it cannot be m. That means from m, we generate m prime.
给发件人，对吗？所以不能是 m。这意味着从 m 生成 m'。
m prime is different. So m prime will not disclose your data information.
m prime 与 m 不同，所以不会泄露您的数据信息。
m cannot be obtained by the sender, and m prime will be signed by sender. So sender will sign
m 无法由发送者获取，m'将由发送者进行签名。因此，发送者将进行签名操作。
m prime to get a signature s prime. So for m prime,
m' 获取签名 s'。因此对于 m'，所以...
we'll assume that we are using the RSA algorithm. So m prime to get signature s prime.
我们假设正在使用 RSA 算法。因此，m 是素数，以获取签名 s。
To generate signature, that means we will use the private key to generate the signature.
生成签名，即使用私钥进行签名操作。
D mod n, we have the signature. But
D mod n，我们得到了特征值，但是
in the RSA, suppose in the RSA, this signature generation algorithm,
在 RSA 中，假设我们讨论的是这个签名生成算法，
the message, I'm using my private key, we generate the signature s prime.
消息是：我正在使用我的私钥，我们生成了 s'签名。
Okay, this s prime will be returned to the sender. So sender now can compute the sender's
好的，这个质数将退还给发送方。因此，发送方现在可以计算发送方的信息了。
signature s of m. That means at the sender side, sender will try to generate s from s prime.
签名 s 的 m。也就是说，在发送方，发送者将尝试从 s 原始值生成 s。
This is the arm blinding procedure. So this is called the blinding procedure.
这是手臂失明操作。所以，我们称之为失明程序。
Now this is the arm blinding procedure. And this s, well, the generation s should equal
现在是手臂失明程序。嗯，这个生成器的值应该是
m to the d mod n equals s. We need to guarantee s. Okay, this s contains to be the correct
m 除以 d 模 n 等于 s。我们必须确保 s 是正确的。好的，这个 s 应该包含正确的部分
signal from the sender. That means it equals the m to the d mod n. So d is the private key of the
发送者的信号。这意味着它等于 m 模 n 的 d。因此，d 是私钥。
sender. So it looks to be quite just like a magic, magical trick, right? I do not have your
发送者说，这看起来就像一个神奇的魔术，对吧？我没有你的信息
private key, but somehow I will generate this s. It contains, it equals the message m
私钥，但不知为何我会生成这个 s。它包含的内容，等同于消息 m
to the d mod n. d is the sender's private key. I don't have it, but I can generate the s.
到 d 模 n。d 是发送者的私钥。我没有，但我可以生成 s。
The process can be viewed in this diagram. Well, this is Alice and this is Bob. Alice is the sender.
该过程可在此图中查看。嗯，这是爱丽丝，这是鲍勃。爱丽丝是发送方。这样的表述更符合中文习惯。
Bob is the sender.
Bob 是信息的发送者。
So what we've done in this process is, in the blinding process, we will multiply m with another
在这个过程中，我们做了这样一件事：在盲法阶段，我们会将 m 与另一个数相乘
key. In the blinding process, in the blinding process, we will multiply m with another data.
在遮蔽过程中，我们会将 m 与另一份数据相乘。
And this data r is called the one-time key.
这组数据被称为一次性密钥，意思是指仅使用一次的密钥。
r is a one-time key, random key. So this r, we will, in fact, Alice will choose the data r. r to be
r 是一个一次性随机密钥。实际上，Alice 会选择数据 r。
one-time key. And m will times r to the e, and then mod p.
一次性密钥。将 m 乘以 r 的 e 次方，然后对 p 取模。这句话经过调整，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
And m will times r to the e, and then mod p. So this m prime will be sent to Bob.
然后将 m 乘以 r 的 e 次方，再对 p 取模。这样得到的 m' 将被发送给 Bob。
Alice will choose this r. This r is unknown to Bob. And in this way, m prime will
爱丽丝将选择这个 r。这个 r 对鲍勃来说是未知的。这样，m 的质数就会是
can conceal the original message m. Is this right?
可以隐藏原始信息 m，这样做是否正确？
The m prime will be sent to Bob. This message contains some random number r.
m'将被发送给鲍勃。此消息包含一个随机数 r。
Bob has no idea about r. Thus, Bob cannot get any information from m.
没有关于 r 的了解，因此 Bob 无法从 m 中获取任何信息。
So Bob will do this signing process. The signing is quite simple to Bob. So Bob will apply his
所以鲍勃将执行这个签字流程。对鲍勃来说，这个过程很简单。因此，鲍勃将执行他的
private key d to sign to generate the signature s prime. The s prime will be returned to Alice.
私钥 d 用于生成签名 s'，该签名将返回给 Alice。
So let's see, s prime equals m prime to the d mod p. So m prime equals m times r e,
好吧，让我们看看，s' 等于 m' 的 d 模 p。因此，m' 等于 m 乘以 r 的 e，这样的表述更为自然和易懂。
this to the d mod p. This equals m to the d times r mod p.
这等于 m 的 d 次方模 p。
To the e d mod p.
到 e d 模 p。
Right? Well, according to RSA algorithm, RSA, we know that
嗯？好吧，根据 RSA 算法，我们了解到
r to the e d is congruent to 1 mod p, or previously with mod n. But here we simply use p.
r 到 e d 同余于 1 模 p，之前用模 n 表示。但在此处，我们直接使用 p。
That's the same thing, right?
这不是同一个问题吗？
So you can refresh your memory. m to the e d is congruent to n mod n.
你可以回忆一下，m 的 e 次方 d 与 n 模 n 同余。
And we apply the public key e, apply the private key d again. We can get the original message m
我们首先使用公钥 e 进行加密，然后使用私钥 d 进行解密，从而恢复出原始信息 m
in the RSA algorithm. So here, the r e d will get back to r, that one time key again,
在 RSA 算法中。因此，这里的红色会回到 r，即那个一次性密钥。
1 mod p. So this one will generate, this one equals m d times r mod p.
1 模 p。因此，这个会生成，即等于 m 乘以 d 再模 p 的结果。
So this is the s prime. Is that clear?
这就是 s 的质数。您明白了吗？
Okay, this s prime will be obtained by Alice.
好的，这个素数将由 Alice 得到。
So Alice got s prime. From s prime, Alice will divide this s prime by r
因此，爱丽丝得到了 s 的质数。然后，她将这个质数 s 除以 r
So she will get m to the d times r divided by r mod p. And this equals m d mod p.
因此，她将得到 m 乘以 d 除以 r 再除以 r 模 p。这等于 m 除以 p 的 d 次方余数。
s prime divided by r equals s prime times r minus 1.
s 倍数除以 r 等于 s 倍数乘以 r 减 1（更自然地表达）。
The times r minus 1, that's a module inverse.
时间是 r 减 1，那是一个模逆。这个表达更自然，易于理解。
So you see, s prime times r equals s prime times r minus 1.
你看，s'乘以 r 等于 s'乘以 r 减 1。
Not because if both sides, we times r, we times r, we mod p, of course this can be canceled, right?
因为如果两边都乘以 r，再乘以 r，然后对 p 取模，自然可以约掉，对吧？
This is prime. And according to definition, r minus 1 times r, this is 1 mod p.
这是素数。根据定义，r 减 1 乘以 r，等于 1 模 p。
So of course, with this s prime divided by r, in fact equals s prime times r minus 1.
当然，用这个 s'除以 r，实际上等于 s'乘以 r 减 1。这样的表达更符合中文的表达习惯。
r minus 1 is a module inverse. So how can we do the division operation?
r 减 1 是模逆，那么我们该如何进行除法操作呢？
Division can be translated to the multiplication of the modular inverse.
除法可以理解为模逆乘积的表示。
Okay, so in nature 2, we studied the modular inverse.
好的，那么在自然 2 中，我们学习了模逆的概念。
We just guarantee modular inverse times the r mod p equals 1. That's a requirement.
我们确保模逆乘以 r 模 p 等于 1，这是必须满足的条件。
The eyes can get s prime from Bob. So eyes will divide s prime by r.
眼睛能从 Bob 那里获得 s prime，因此会将 s prime 除以 r。
Or we say s prime times r to the minus 1. Then we can get this is s.
我们说 s 倍的 r 的负一次方，那么就可以得到这是 s。
For message m, it's signature to be signed by Bob. This signature is m to the d mod p.
对于消息 m，其签名应由 Bob 签署。该签名是 m 对 p 取模后的结果。
So this for Bob, the public key is e p. This is the public key. And private key
这是对 Bob 的，公钥是 e p。这是公钥。私钥
is d, right? For Bob. Then you can see this is indeed
是的，对 Bob 来说没错。然后你可以看到这确实是对的
is generated by using Bob's private key based on the original message m.
该内容是通过使用基于原始消息 m 的 Bob 的私钥生成的。翻译更加自然，易于理解。
We have this signature. Although Alice has no idea of Bob's private key,
我们有这个签名。尽管爱丽丝对鲍勃的私钥一无所知，
but she can successfully generate the signature s. In this signing process,
但是她能够成功生成签名 s。在签名过程中，
Bob has no idea of the original message m. So eyes can know this r.
没有了解原始信息 m，因此眼睛可以看出这个 r。
Of course, eyes can calculate r minus 1. When eyes obtain s prime from Bob,
当然，眼睛可以计算出 r 减 1。当眼睛从 Bob 那里得到 s' 后，
so eyes can calculate s prime times r minus 1 mod p, then this equals the signature s.
可以计算 s 的素数倍减 1 模 p，那么这个结果就是签名 s（使翻译更自然、易懂）。
So this is the blind signature generation process.
这就是盲签名生成过程的描述。
We have the charms plus signature scheme. This scheme is exactly the process illustrated in this page.
我们拥有魅力加签名方案。这正是本页所展示的过程，翻译更加自然易懂。
So you can see in this transplant signature, we assume that we're using the RSA algorithm.
因此，您可以从这次移植签名中看出，我们假定使用了 RSA 算法。
And suppose Bob's public key is n and e. His private key is d. The message is m.
假设鲍勃的公钥为 n 和 e，私钥为 d，信息为 m。
m should be smaller than n. And Alice chooses a one-time key k.
m 应该小于 n，Alice 选择一个一次性密钥 k。
k should be in the range from 0 to n. We will guarantee that gcd n k is 1.
k 应该位于 0 到 n 的区间内。我们保证 n 和 k 的最大公约数为 1。
So this will guarantee that we have the k must 1 mod n.
这将确保我们拥有满足 1 模 n 的 k。
k is a randomly chosen number. This is called the blinding factor.
k 是一个随机选取的数字，被称为盲化因子。
In the blinding process, Alice will compute n times k to the e. Alice knows k.
在曝光过程中，Alice 需要计算 n 次 k 的 e 次方。她已知 k 的值。
And in this blinding process, well, when Bob applied his signature, applied his private key d,
在这个令人眼花缭乱的流程中，鲍勃应用了他的签名和私钥 d，嗯，是这样的
and this m prime d equals this one.
这 m 的导数等于这个（更自然的翻译）。
m to the d times k times e d.
m 乘以 d，再乘以 k，最后是 e 的 d 次方。这样的表达更符合中文习惯。
Well, in this way, the random number k with an exponent d can be actually can be cancelled.
嗯，这样就可以实际上取消掉具有指数 d 的随机数 k 了。
We already put the exponent part with a value of e. So e times d mod n. Actually, this equals 1.
我们已经将指数部分赋值为 e，即 e 乘以 d 再对 n 取模。实际上，这个结果等于 1。
So in the on-branded case, we have a random number k with an exponent d.
在品牌未使用的情况下，存在一个随机数 k 和指数 d。
Actually, this equals 1. So in the on-branding, the message we want to get from s prime to s.
实际上，这等于 1。所以在品牌推广中，我们希望从 s'传达给 s 的信息。
So s prime is the signature obtained by Alice. So Alice can get
因此，S'是 Alice 获得的签名。因此，Alice 可以获取到...（此处根据上下文补充具体内容）
s prime times the k must 1. So this will get the original signature.
s 乘以 k 必须等于 1，所以这将获取原始签名。
The reason is because s prime, this is s prime.
原因在于 s 是一个素数，这正是 s 的特性。
So s prime equals m d is equal to m d times k mod n. So from s prime to s,
因此，s' 等于 m d，等于 m d 乘以 k 模 n。从 s' 到 s，
we can simply multiply s prime by k must 1. This will generate the signature s.
我们只需将 s'乘以 k（必须为 1），就能生成签名 s。
So this is the whole process. You can see this is the m prime. m prime to d, we have m d, this is s, this is k.
这就是整个流程。你可以看到这是 m 的导数。从 m 导数到 d，我们有 md，这是 s，这是 k。
You have mod n, e d.
您有模数 n，e d。
In our RSA algorithm, e d, we choose e d such that it equals, it is congruent to 1 mod phi.
在我们的 RSA 算法中，我们选择 e 和 d，使得它们与φ同余 1。这样的选择使得 e 和 d 更加自然且易于理解。
This is a guarantee that k e d mod n equals k.
这是一种保证，即 k 除以 n 的余数等于 k。
So thus, we can get the s. This is the signature.
因此，我们可以得到这个 s。这便是签名。
And this signature equals this part
这个签名等同于这一部分
is s prime.
它是质数吗？
Okay, now we look at this exercise. Suppose we have the copy key to be
好的，现在我们来分析这个练习。假设我们拥有复制键为
e equals 5, n is 1, 1, 9. So 1, 1, 9 equals 7 times 17, right?
e 等于 5，n 分别为 1、1、9，那么 1、1、9 就是 7 乘以 17，对吧？
This p to be 7, q to be 17. The requester wants a signature on the message m equals
这 p 等于 7，q 等于 17。请求者在消息 m 上要求签名。
37. Suppose he chooses a random blending factor R to be 29. So we need to guarantee that g c d
37. 假设他随机选取一个混合因子 R 为 29，因此需要保证 gcd
R n is 1. In this way, we can calculate our must 1 mod n.
Rn 等于 1，这样我们就可以计算 1 对 n 的模了。
So what's the private key of Sonar? We have the public key, e and n. We are able to calculate
那么，Sonar 的私钥是什么？我们已经有了公钥 e 和 n，能够计算出
the Sonar's private key. And then we should apply the blending phase.
这是声纳的私钥，接下来应进行混合处理阶段。
So suppose this step 1, step 2, blending phase, step 3, signing phase, step 4 on blending phase.
假设这一步骤包括 1、2、混合阶段、3、签署阶段、4 在混合阶段。
In the blending phase, that means the message m times R is one time key. We apply the same
在混合阶段，这意味着消息 m 乘以 R 是一次密钥。我们采用相同的处理方式。
message m times R is one time key. We apply the public key of the Sonar, right?
消息 m 次 R 对应一个密钥。我们使用 Sonar 的公钥，对吗？
This is the blending phase. We get m prime. In the signing phase,
这是混合阶段。我们得到 m'。在签名阶段，
this is quite simple. The Sonar will apply his private key to do the signing. That's the m prime
这非常简单。Sonar 会使用其私钥进行签名，这就是 m 的质数
to apply the private key d to generate the s prime. In the on-blending phase, it is
将私钥 d 应用于生成 s'。在混合阶段，它用于...
done by the requester. He will get the signature s from s prime times R one time key,
由请求者完成。他将获得从 s'乘以 R 一次密钥得到的签名，表达更为自然。
the module inverse of this R mod n.
这个 R 模 n 的逆元模块（经过润色）。
OK, so this is an exercise. Let's have a break for 10 minutes. So in 10 minutes,
好的，这是一个练习。那么我们先休息 10 分钟吧。再过 10 分钟，
you can try to solve this exercise. OK, so let's have a break for 10 minutes.
你可以尝试完成这个练习。好的，让我们休息 10 分钟。